Kanba - The Building Under Construction - Few days ago - It's a surprise. I never thought Tabuki would seek revenge. I hid it though to the end. This is a secret I can't reveal.
Where is your father?
父親はどこだ
Not with me.
いない　どこにいるか知らない
I don't know where he is.
I see.
そっか
ひまり
Himari!
嘘をつくのはよくないな
You really shouldn't lie.
I really don't know where he is.
ホントに親父の行方は知らないんだ
Ogikubo's
flavor
Rina-chan
Is your hand better now?
もう手は大丈夫なの
あー　大げさな感じに見えるだけ
Yeah, it looks worse than it is.
It's nothing serious.
大した怪我じゃないよ
冠葉　お前はホントによくやっている
Kanba, you're doing really well.
I am proud of you as a father.
父として誇らしく思う
I'm really proud of you.
自慢の息子ね
ミッションを遂行するまで　俺達は家に戻れない
We can't return home until we carry out the mission.
それまで　冠葉
Until then, Kanba... you have to protect the Takakura family.
お前が高倉家を守るんだ
Help out Shoma and Himari.
晶馬とひまりを助けてあげてね
Yeah.
あー
The usual, for my son.
息子にいつものものを
少年少女輪になって
shounen shoujo wa ni natte
The boys and girls form a ring
伸ばした手は空を切って落ちる
nobashita te wa kuu wo kitte ochiru
Extended hands cut down through the air
交わらないイマジナリー
majiwaranai imaginary
The Imaginary and the Real can never mingle
回転木馬宙を舞って
kaiten mokuba chuu wo matte
The merry-go-round twirls into the air
戦いの幕を切って落とす
tatakai no maku wo kitte otosu
As the curtain of war is torn open
秘め事明かすホーリーナイト
himegoto akasu holy night
The Holy Night for divulging secrets
mayonaka hiraku mado temaneku nazo no koe
My window opens at night and a mysterious voice beckons
真夜中開く窓
手招く謎の声
shinku no curtain wo hirugaeshite hohoemi kakusu
A crimson curtain conceals the smile
深紅のカーテンを翻して
微笑み隠す
shounen yo ware ni kaere
Boys, come back to me
少年よ我に帰れ
特急列車乗っちゃって
tokkyuu ressha nocchate
I ended up getting on the midnight express
ネバーランドに連れてって
neverland ni tsuretette
Take me away to Neverland
一切合切奪ってよ
issai gassai ubatte yo
Steal away everything I have
後ろ指さされたって
ushiro yubi sasaretatte
I don't care if you talk behind my back
一目散に逃げちゃっていいよ
ichimokusan ni nigechatte iiyo
I'll just run away at full speed
全部お気に召すまま
zenbu oki ni mesu mama
Do as you please
少年少女輪になって
shounen shoujo wa ni natte
The boys and girls form a ring
伸ばした手は空を切って落ちる
nobashita te wa kuu wo kitte ochiru
Extended hands cut down through the air
回り始めるディステニー
mawari hajimeru destiny
Destiny begins to turn
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听：hunter 翻译:草泥马 校对:冷漠的风  木落 时间轴:花开 压制:wcaster
Choloroplasts on plant's leaves convert energy in sunlight,
（植物の葉にある葉緑体）
（これが光エネルギーを使って）
along with water and CO2 to...
（水と二酸化炭素から）
な　多蕗　学校やめたらしいぜ
I heard Tabuki quit his job.
Huh? How come?
え　なんで
さあー
Dunno.
But he hasn't shown up in a while, right?
けど　ここんとこずっと休んでただろ
（この一連の反応を　我々は光合成と呼んで）
You think it's stress and that kind of stuff?
なに　ストレスとかそういうの
He seemed really serious about his job, so...
真面目そうなやつだったからな
（今日は自然界のさまざまな条件下における光合成の変化を見ていきましょう）
（蒸散の仕組みについては）
Thank you for everything
you've done for me.
Farewell.
Yuri - The Cafe That Serves Fabulous Mont Blanc - Curry Day / We made the promise on that day. By being together, we should be able to make Momoka an eternal existence.
Curry Day
結婚
Marriage?
え　私達は一緒にいるべきだと思うの
Yes.
I think we should be together.
You think?
そう かな
Yeah!
そうよ　私とあなたは運命の輪で繋がれてる
You and I are bound by the wheel of fate.
桃果で僕達が繋がるって言うのかい
Are you saying Momoka is binding us together?
We will be with Momoka for eternity if we become family.
私達が家族になれば　桃果とも永遠に一緒よ
家族
Family...
無理だ
That's impossible.
We'll just pretend at first.
家族のふりから始めるの
いずれ私達　ホントの家族になれるわ
But eventually, we'll become a real family.
It was impossible for us, after all.
やっぱり　私達には無理だった
No matter.
いいわ　私は一人で桃果を取り戻すから
I'll bring back Momoka by myself.
That should've been the plan all along.
最初からそうすればよかったのよ
But only half of the spell needed to transfer fate is written here.
でも　ここには　運命を乗り換える呪文は半分しか書かれていない
I need the other half of the diary to find out the rest.
残りを知るためには もう片方の日記が必要
寒いわ　この部屋
This room is so cold.
Cheers!
乾杯
Welcome Home. Congratulations!!
Congratulations for being released from the hospital, Himari!
ひまり　退院おめでとう
Good for you, Himari!
よかったね　ひまりちゃん
Thank you.
ありがとう
But I still need regular checkups.
でも　まだ通院しなきゃだけど
Don't worry about it.
気にするな　そんなこと
そうだよ　ひまりがうちに帰ってきたって事が大事なんだ
Yeah!
Important thing is that you're back home.
また皆揃って御飯が食べられるのも お祝いしなきゃ
We can eat together again!
That's a reason to celebrate!
Sukiyaki tonight, as promised!
約束通り　今夜はすき焼きだ
Ohhh!
芸術的
It's like a work of art!
I bought the most expensive meat in store for the first time in my life.
人生初　店で一番高い肉を買ってきた
Hold on, how much was it per gram?
って　これグラムいくら
Don't be stingy.
けちるなよ
I got my paycheck from my part-time job.
バイト代も入ったし　これぐらいの贅沢はしないとな
We have to live it up!
兄貴 まさか変なバイトとかしてないよね
Don't tell me you're doing something sketchy.
Huh?
Like being a host or something... you've been coming home late these days.
ホストとか　最近夜遅いし
Rosanjin Style
What? Really?
そうなの
Kan...
冠ちゃん
No way! Geez!
バカ　んなわけないだろ
よし　肉入れるぞ
Anyway, I'm throwing in the meat.
Shoma, pass the eggs.
晶馬　卵くばれ
あ　その前に
Oh, before that, Himari has an important announcement.
今日はひまりちゃんから大事なお知らせが
Kan, Sho.
冠ちゃん　晶ちゃん
Thank you always taking such good care of me.
いつもありがとう
Um...
えっと　今日は兄弟に感謝の日です
It's a Brother Appreciation Day.
ひまり
Himari...
これ
Is this...
いいから　開けてみて
Just open it.
Thank you, Himari!
ありがとう　ひまり
You were knitting them for us in the hospital.
やっぱり病院で編んでたのは僕達のだったんだね
うん　びっくりさせたくて内緒にしてたの
Yes.
We kept it a secret to surprise you.
ごめんね
Sorry.
大きさどう
How do they fit?
Perfectly!
ぴったりだよ
What about the color? The design?
色は　デザインは
うん　悪くないな
Not bad at all!
そっか　よかった
I see, that's good.
We nailed it this time!
今度はばっちりだったね
What?
何だよ
Not telling!
内緒　ね
Right?
It's really warm!
でもこれホントにあったかいよ
Hey, I helped pick the yarn.
ね　その毛糸　あたしも一緒に選んだんだよ
It was really hard to find a color that would look good on you!
晶馬君に似合う色探すの　とっても大変だったんだぞ
Himari! I'll cherish it for the rest of my life!
ひまり　一生大切にするよ
Hey, are you listening?
ちょっと　聞いてるの
Hey!
ちょっと
イッテッテ
あたしの話聞いてなかったでしょう
You weren't listening to me, were you?
What?
なんだよ
You two sure get along well.
二人は仲良しだね
What?!
うん　やっぱり高い肉は美味いな
Expensive meat sure are delicious!
Kan, you'll turn into a cow.
冠ちゃん　牛になるよ
What do you want from moo?
なんだよ　モン
あ　私が
I'll wash...
Don't worry!
いいの　いいの
ひまりちゃんは主役なんだから　座ってて
You're the guest of honor! Just relax.
Oh, okay.
あ　うん
Thanks.
あ　ありがとう
Can I leave them in here?
ここでいい
Yes.
うん　油汚れは先に落とすから
I'll scrub them first.
When you're done, I'll wash them.
じゃあ　そのあと　あたしが洗うね
Use that apron if you want.
よかったら　そこのエプロン使って
Okay.
うん
It must have been electrifying,
痺れただろう
to spend time with just your family.
久しぶりに家族　水入らずで
Yes...
うん
どうかしたの
Is something wrong?
I know...
私　知ってるよ
that you let me leave the hospital because my illness can't be cured.
病気　もう治らないから退院させてくれたんでしょう
It seems you gave it a lot of thought.
随分考えたようだね
Is that your conclusion?
そう思うのかい
It's obvious!
誰だって　分かるよ
You're giving me more medicine, yet...
お薬の量は増えてるのに　おかしい
Something's wrong.
I'm going to die.
私は死ぬのね
You won't.
死なないよ
You're lying.
嘘
What do you want me to say?
どんな言葉を言ってほしいのかな
I'm sorry, something was wrong with me.
ごめんなさい　どうかしてたね
ホントの事を言っちゃいなよ
Tell me the truth.
How to Create
Your Comfortable
Place of Belonging.
あ　あのね
Well, it feels like I don't belong in my home anymore.
なんだか　家から私の居場所がなくなっていくような気がするの
I hate this...
嫌だな　どうしてこんな気持ちになっちゃうのかな
Why do I feel this way?
When everyone is worried about me.
皆が私の事心配してくれてるのに
Where you belong, huh?
居場所か
Where do you belong?
君の居場所ってどこ　君は自分をどうしたいの
What do you want to do with yourself?
I-I want things to stay the way they are.
わ 私はこのままでいたいの
With Kan, Sho and I...
冠ちゃんと晶ちゃんと私で　ずっと　このまま
How to Create
Your Comfortable
Place of Belonging.
The three of us together.
Are you sure about that?
それでいいの
What?
When you realize how you really feel, something precious to you will crumble.
自分のホントの気持ちに気がつくと　大切な物が壊れてしまう
That's what you think.
君はそう思っている
Wh-What do you mean?
な　何の事
Who knows? I don't know your feelings, your truth, or your past.
さあー
僕には君の気持ち　君の真実　君の過去は分からないさ
Tell me, what is the meaning of this so-called spell written in here?
そろそろ　教えて
ここに書かれてるっていう呪文とやらに何の意味があるの
Nothing in particular.
なにも
It's just like "Open Sesame".
開け　ゴマと同じさ
A spell is just a spell, nothing more.
呪文にそれ以外の意味はないよ
What are you saying?
なにそれ
That it's magic?
魔法ってこと
Ali Baba and the
Forty Thieves
Yes.
そうさ
Complete the spell to save your brother's life.
呪文を完成させて　弟の命を救う
It's a fate transfer.
運命の乗り換えだよ
You must be kidding.
冗談よね
Carrot :>
You're a doctor.
貴方は医者だもの
"Spell" must be an analogy or code for a new medicine-
呪文っていうのは新薬の開発に必要な暗号かなにかのたとえでは
That's just your assumption.
それは君の思い込み
Then it really is...
じゃあ　ホントに
Yes. I'm a magician.
うん　僕は魔法使いなんだ
How to Live
Without
Being Deceived
Don't take me for a fool!
いい加減にして
What are you really after?
貴方のホントの目的は何
To put this world back on track.
この間違った世界を正したい
That's a lie!
嘘
It's the truth.
ホントさ
What are you trying to make Kanba do?
貴方は　冠葉に何をさせたいの
I will have the children accomplish what their parents could not.
君達の親が叶えられなかった夢を　その子供達に実現してもらうんだ
No, I will not allow that to happen!
やめて　そんなこと　私が許さない
You're not getting on the train of fate?
君は運命の列車に乗らないんだね
Not a chance.
乗らないわ　冠葉も乗らせない
I won't let Kanba either!
She was upset.
怒ってましたね
She was mad.
かんかんでしたね
I wonder if that was enough to make her burn the diary.
彼女　これで日記を燃やしてくれるかな
After all, I can't do it myself.
僕にはそれができないからね
Impressive!
さすがです
Electrifying!
痺れました
I can't win the game with that thing around.
あれがあると　僕はゲームに勝てないんだよ
Yes, this thing is to blame for...
そうよ　こんな物があるから
What if I really needed this to save Mario?
もし　マリオさんを救うために　これがホントに必要だとしたら
Kanba...
冠葉　どうして貴方は私のそばにいてくれないの
Why won't you be here with me?
Yes, it's all that family's fault.
そうよ　皆あの家がいけないのよ
That girl's fault!
あの娘が
Today's
Slogan
I wonder if we can stay this way forever.
僕達　ずっとこのままでいられるのかな
Truths born from lies
We always will.
ずっと　今のままだ
No matter what happens,
何が起きても　俺が高倉家を守ってみせる
I'll protect the Takakura family.
でも　またあんな事があったら
But if something like that were to happen again...
Don't worry.
心配するな　罰はもう　俺が受けた
I've already taken the punishment.
あの人達のせいだ
It's all their fault.
Huh?
Our parents.
父さんと母さん
I will never forgive them.
僕は絶対に許さない
だって　そうだろう
Just think about it!
Tabuki wasn't the only one... many people still hate us.
多蕗だけじゃない　いまでも　大勢の人が僕達を恨んでる
It's all our parents' fault.
みんなあの二人のせいじゃないか
Himari's illness too...
ひまりの病気だって
Cut it out.
止せよ
We don't need parents.
僕達に親はいらない
そうだよね
Isn't that right?
Yeah, you're right.
あー　そうだな
My true feelings.
ホントの私の気持ち
私の真実
My truth.
My past.
私の過去
Coming!
はい
Yes? Who is it?
はい　どちら様ですか
嫌だわ　早くすり潰さないと
Gosh, I must crush her soon.
What?
これ　つまらない物だけど
This is my humble gift.
Kanba is... not here?
冠葉は　いないわね
What? Um...
え　あの
I'm going to let myself in.
上がらせていただくわ
This home is decorated in such bad taste.
何だか趣味の悪い家ね
How long does he intend to live in this dump?
こんなあばら家にいつまで暮らすつもりなのかしら
Have some tea.
お茶　どうぞ
Um...
あのう
I'm sorry.
すみません　また冠ちゃんがなにかしたんですよね
Kan must have done something to you.
Huh?
But Kan actually is a very kind person.
でも　ホントは冠ちゃんとってもいい人なんです
He's a bit of a playboy, but he doesn't mean any harm.
ちょっとすけこましなだけで
悪気はないんです　貴方を傷つけるつもりは
He didn't mean to hurt you-
What are you talking about?
何を言っているの　私はただ返してもらいに来ただけよ
I'm just here to get something back.
あ　もしかして　何か高価なプレゼントを冠ちゃんに
Did you give him an expensive present of sorts?
Yes... I have given him countless presents.
そうね　贈物ならこれまで随分としてきたわ
Although, he refused to accept any of them.
全部突き返されたけど
Don't tell me, it's the sukiyaki from the other day?
まさか　この間のすき焼き
What?
なに
I-I'm sorry!
ご　ごめんなさい　もしかすると　貴方の高いプレゼント　お肉に化けちゃったかもしれません
Maybe your expensive present turned into meat!
How can my present turn into meat?
私のプレゼントが　お肉に化けたりするものですか
Oh, maybe it's still in the house.
じゃあ　まだ家にあるかも
I'll go look for it.
探します
What did you give him?
冠ちゃんに何を
Love.
愛
Love?!
Um...
えっと　それは無理かも
I don't think I can get it back for you.
No, you will return it to me.
いいえ　返していただくわ
でも　そればかりは冠ちゃん次第というか
But... that's up to Kan...
It's not something his sister could...
妹の私からはなんとも
You're calling yourself Kanba's sister?
貴方が冠葉の妹
That's a good one.
面白い冗談ね
Um, it's not a joke.
あの　冗談じゃなくて
I really am his sister.
ホントに　私　妹なんです
If you've mistaken me for his girlfriend...
冠ちゃんの彼女と勘違いしているのなら
You're the one who's mistaken.
勘違いは貴方の方でしょう　ひまりさん
Himari.
A girl who's annoying to no end.
どこまでも図図しい子　虫酸が走るわ
You make me sick.
You're not even his real family.
ホントの家族でもないくせに
Kanba can't come back to me because you're still pretending to be his sister!
貴方がいつまでも妹のふりをしているから
冠葉は私のところに帰って来られない
Give Kanba back to me!
冠葉を返して
No truth can be born from lies!
嘘で固めた物に真実なんて生まれやしない
P-Please...
か　帰って　帰ってください
Please leave.
I see.
そう　記憶にないというのね
You have no recollection of it.
Then, I'll help you remember.
なら　思い出させてあげる
This is a custom-made recollection ball.
これは特別製の思い出し玉
You will find out just what you are.
これで貴方も自分が何者であるか　思い知るでしょう
Do not look away from the truth!
目を背けては駄目
Who are you?
貴方は誰
Why are you here?
何故ここにいるの
What do you want?
何をしたいの
Who knows? I don't know your feelings, your truth, or your past.
さあー
僕には君の気持ち　君の真実　君の過去は分からないさ
I'm...
私は
It's raining, Himari.
ひまり　雨だよ
Our laundry is all wet-
洗濯物が台無し
Sheesh, I was almost home-
参ったな　もうちょっとで濡れずに済ん
Your forehead is mine!
そのおでこ　いただくわ
What are you doing?
何するんだ
Why are you here?
何故お前がここにいる
I'm here to take back my love... my past!
取り返しに来たのよ
私の愛を　私の過去を　私の真実を
My truth!
You can't hide from me.
隠れても無駄よ
You will return what you have stolen from me.
私から奪った物を返してもらうわ
Don't, Masako!
止せ　真砂子
You sneaky little rat!
すばしこい小ネズミね
The time to crush you has finally come.
ようやく　すり潰す時が来たわね
Remember everything.
すべてを思い出すのよ　真実からは逃れられない
You can't escape from the truth!
Himari - Child Broiler - I remembered. There is someone precious to me. That day, in the Frozen World, I met my fate.
Where am I?
ここはどこ
知らないの　ここはいらない子供達が集められる場所なんだ
Don't you know?
This is where unneeded children are gathered.
I'm an unneeded child?
私は いらない子供
If you stay in here long enough, you'll turn into an invisible entity,
ここにずっといるとね
透明な存在になって　やがて　この世から消えてしまうんだ
and eventually cease to exist in this world.
Disappear? Me?
消えてしまう　私が
Yes.
そう　砕かれて　粉々にされて
We will be crushed into pieces.
We will become invisible.
僕達は透明になってしまうんだよ
Child Broiler Administration
I see.
そっか　でも
But I can take this with me, right?
きっと　これだけは持っていけるよね
Goodbye myself, who never amounted to anything.
さようなら　何者にもなれなかった私
No, don't go!
駄目だ　行かないで
You can't go!
行っちゃ　駄目だ
Who is it?
誰
It's me.
僕だよ　一緒に帰ろう
Come with me.
Where to?
どこへ　私にはもう帰る場所はないの
I don't have a place to return to.
Come home, with me.
うちに帰るんだよ　僕と一緒に
Your home?
貴方の家
Yes.
そう　僕達は家族になるんだ
We will become family.
How?
どうやって　私は貴方の家族じゃないよ
I'm not your family.
Don't worry, we have magic!
平気さ　僕らには魔法がある
Let's share the fruit of fate.
運命の果実を　一緒に食べよう
Thank you for choosing me.
選んでくれて　ありがとう
I remember it now.
思い出した　私が運命の果実を分け合ったのは晶ちゃんだ
The person I shared the fruit of fate with me was...
Sho.
Sho is my...
晶ちゃんが私の
My Soulmate
kagayaiteta today kara
Everything shines starting today
輝いてた　 十代から
hitomi no oku ni yakitsuita omoide ga aru darou
There must memories burned into your brain
瞳の奥に
焼き付いた思い出があるだろう
ai wo kakushi
Hide your love
愛を隠し　愛を探し
ai wo sagashi
Find your love
kodoku ni taete
Endure your loneliness
孤独に耐えて
nannimo naritakunai nante uso sa
It's a lie when you say you don't want to amount to anything
何にもなりたくないなんて嘘さ
HIDE and SEEK
Hide and  seek　希望は遠くで
kibou wa tooku
Distant hope
HIDE and SEEK
Hide and  seek　輝きだけ　青く強く放つ
kagayaki dake aoku tsuyoku hanatsu
Only shines in bright blue
HIDE and SEEK
Hide and  seek　憎しみ合いながら
nikushimi ai nagara
Hating each other
HIDE and SEEK
Hide and  seek　涙もなく
namidamo naku onaji beddo de nemuru
Sleep in same bed without tears
同じベッドで　眠る
I thought I was alone the whole time.
ずっと一人だと思っていた
That day, in that Frozen World,
あの日　あの氷の世界で
I met my fate.
私は運命と出会ったんだ
Lily Hoshino
Survival Strategy, playboy.
生存戦略　すけこまし